FRANKIE DIXON

SENIOR FRONT END ENGINEER

CONTACT ↓ 413-218-6421 ☑ fdixon7@gmail.com ⑤ Boston, Massachusetts TECH STACK HTML5/CSS3/JS/jQuery Tailwind CSS Post CSS Node Rest API Django React

EDUCATION

BSc - Plant, Soil, & Insect Sciences

University of Massachusetts

2008 - 2011

Worked in comparative genomics laboratory while a full-time student

ASc - Computer Sciences

Springfield Technical CC

2003 - 2006

AWARDS

Maverick Award

Awarded "Maverick Award" (Employee of the Year) from Windsor Marketing Group, for leveraging unique solutions to solve problems

Prudential Impact Awards

Received seven Impact Awards from Prudential, for employees who go above and beyond to drive business outcomes

PROFILE

A Senior Front End Engineer with 15+ years of experience in developing of high-performance e-commerce solutions and teams. I specialize in HTML5, CSS3, JS/jQuery, Tailwind CSS, Django, Node, and React. I've managed teams of front-end specialists, focusing on code quality, team velocity, and web accessibility. My leadership roles have involved vendor management, stakeholder engagement, and mentorship of developers, solidified by industry accolades for innovation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Front End Engineer

Undercover Tourist

2021 - Present

- I lead a small team, focusing on complex e-commerce solutions
- Replaced legacy front-end framework, reducing CSS bundle size by 50% and accelerating product development
- · Refactored legacy scripts, added new site functionalities, reduced asset payloads
- Collaborated on RESTful API integration for new products
- Ensured website accessibility, optimized for SEO, and implemented front end best practices

Senior User Experience Developer

LATICRETE International

2020 - 2021

- Led corporate website overhaul, implementing new information architecture
- · Authored UI for web and mobile apps, focusing on performance and scalability
- Developed component library to standardize and accelerate feature development
- Engineered React JS web apps in a greenfield environment

Senior User Experience Developer

Prudential Financial

2017 - 2020

- Led the development of interactive tools and a templated website builder
- Managed the development and testing cycle of new digital products
- Collaborated on interactive prototypes to validate functionality and user flow
- Oversaw vendors for web application development and accessibility compliance
- Facilitated technical workshops to accelerate iterative design adoption

User Experience Developer

The Walker Group

2014 - 2017

- Engineered e-commerce solutions, emphasizing performance and scalability
- Transformed user feedback into iterative improvements, boosting conversion
- Authored e-commerce website, leading to 100%+ increase in goal completion
- Migrated a consumer goods website to an open-source platform, reducing costs and improving conversion rates

Front End Developer

Idea Agency

2012 - 2014

- Collaborated on website development across multiple industries in a design agency
- Authored marketing landing pages and email campaigns to promote conversion

Genomics Data Engineer

University of Massachusetts Amherst

2008 - 2011

- Leveraged high-throughput computing to analyze genomic data
- Used open source tools to develop genetic markers for mRNA sequence tagging

Front End Developer

Windsor Marketing Group

2005 - 2008